Preliminary Guide to the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education records, 1965-1975
Duke University. University Archives
Office of Career Development and Continuing Education records 1965-1975
Duke University. Office of Career Development and Continuing Education.
2.5 linear feet
Duke University. University Archives
Contains the records of the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education at Duke University, established in 1972 to assist undergraduates and non-degree students in preparing for careers. The Office worked closely with the Placement Services Office, the Counseling Center, and the academic deans of Trinity College of Arts and Sciences. Also contains the records of the Directions for Educated Women Committee (formerly known as the Educated WomanPower Committee), established in 1966. The student and faculty Directions for Educated Women Committee organized programs to introduce career options and role models of successful career women to female undergraduates. Types of materials include correspondence, course evaluations, brochures, newsletters, clippings, reports, handbooks, fliers, and short writings. Major subjects include Duke University, career guidance, Office of Continuing Education, Office of Career Development and Continuing Education, community service, internships, and women college students. Materials range in date from 1965-1975. English.
UA.25.43.0002
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
Provenance
Transfer; 1980; 80-64
Transfer; 1975; 75-71
Transfer; 1974; 74-71
Historical Note
The Office of Career Development and Continuing Education, active at Duke University from about 1969 to 1975, provided undergraduate and continuing education students with assistance in establishing career goals. In cooperation with the University Counseling Center, the Office of Placement Services, and deans in the undergraduate colleges and professional schools, the Office sponsored the Apprenticeship Program and the Continuing Education Program. The Apprenticeship Program arranged volunteer placement in community businesses and agencies. The Continuing Education Program placed students in local schools to work as teachers, tutors, and assistants. Other internship projects included helping local Girl Scouts groups, working in hospitals, counseling older adults, and acting as mentors to at-risk youth. Although the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education worked with both men and women, the Office was especially collaborative with student groups interested in women's programs and studies.
Office of Career Development and Continuing Education also worked with other campus organizations to bring professionals to speak on campus about the issues of young women in a professional work environment, particularly Directions for Educated Women Committee, a student and faculty group at Trinity College. Directions for Educated Women Committee came together in 1966 when students from Trinity College expressed concerns for women's career orientation programs, especially the fact that there was an absence of centralized information for women to learn about careers. In response, the Committee was formed and promptly arranged a series of speakers. Various women professionals addressed preparation for graduate work, admission requirements for graduate schools, combining marriage and a career, and suggested opportunities for young women in their field.
Around 1975, the name of the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education changed to the Office of Continuing Education. The Office continued to perform many of the same services for students, but with less focus on young women professionals. With the development of the Women's Studies Program at Duke University (1983) and the Women's Center (1989), career resources for women continue to be available.
Collection Overview
Contains materials relating to the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education at Duke University, including significant topical files on women in higher education, professional women role models, and development of women's career conferences. Also contains records of Directions for Educated Women Committee, a women faculty and student committee active from about 1966 until the early 1970s. Types of materials include correspondence, course evaluations, brochures, newsletters, clippings, reports, handbooks, fliers, and short writings. Materials range in date from 1965-1975.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Center for Career Development and Continuing Education; Duke University. Office of Continuing Education; Duke University -- Students; Duke University. Woman's College -- History; Career education -- North Carolina; Counseling in higher education; Occupational training for women; Vocational guidance -- North Carolina -- Durham; Vocational guidance for women -- North Carolina; Women college students; Women -- Employment
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- Container List:
  - Tutoring, projects, correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
  - Course evaluations, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Internships in social services, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
  - Course materials, fliers, brochures, lists, notes, correspondence, course evaluations, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Internship announcements in Spectrum newsletter, ca. 1972 (Box 1)
  - Handbooks, continuing education, general internship, ca. 1974-1979 (Box 2)
  - Internship announcements, notes and correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
  - Internship evaluations, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
  - Directions for Educated Women Committee conference materials, correspondence, fliers, brochures, annual reports, 1965-1971 (Box 2)
  - Directions for Educated Women Committee, annual reports, 1965-1971 (Box 2)
  - Engineering program correspondence, ca. 1975 (Box 2)
  - General engineering jobs recruiting (Box 2)
  - YWCA (Box 2)
  - Women in Action (Box 2)
  - Episcopal Student Center (Box 2)
  - National Organization for Women, task force and conference materials, ca. 1975 (Box 2)
  - Women in higher education reports (Box 2)
  - Early women's studies pamphlets (Box 2)
  - U.S. Department of Labor, discussion on women in the work force and general education of women (Box 2)
  - Conference materials (Box 2)
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Directions for Educated Women (DEW) materials (Box 2)
  - Status of women in Research Triangle Park businesses (Box 2)
  - Bibliographies on women (for courses and general reference) (Box 2)
Appointments Office records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Center for Continuing Education and Summer Session records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Office of Continuing Education records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Office of Placement Services records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Women's Center records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Women's Studies records.
University Archives, Duke University.